I am Kuuya Amrulineulka, ruler of Kunekamun.
余がクンネカムン王
アムルリネウルカ・クーヤだ
What is the matter?
ん？　どうした
Nothing, I am...
いや
Oh, you need not introduce yourself.
私は
ああ そなたの紹介はいらぬ
I had an investigation done on you, so I
believe I know most everything about you.
事前に調べさせていたから
大体のことは知ってるつもりだ
You are a man I find most interesting.
そなた
中々興味深い男だ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
The Young Sovereign
I hear that you use unheard of methods
to enrich barren fields,
そなた
聞いたことの無い技で
痩せた土地を豊かにし
and that you have lead various tribes
of the lower castes in a rebellion.
多種の下級層部族を率いて
謀反を起こしたという
ついには朝廷を倒し
You finally overthrew the imperial court
and reign as the new emperor.
新しきオウルォとして君臨
And now, I hear you have defeated
the Shikeripechim as well.
そして
あのシケリペチムを
打ち破ったというではないか
Well...
それは
教えてくれ
Tell me, how were you able to do such things?
どうやって
そのような真似が出来たのだ？
さあ 言ってみるがよい
Come! Do not hesitate to tell me.
Huh? What is the matter?
どうした？
I merely attempt to always do what is best.
私は
常に最善の方法を考えるように
努めただけだ
And if it had not been for everyone's help,
I could never have accomplished what I did.
それに皆がいなかったら
到底叶うものではなかった
それだけか
Is that all?
Is that not enough?
それが？
まさか
How could it be? So you say that you
did not use any special powers?
では何か特別な力を
使ったのではないというのか
ん 信じられぬ
I cannot believe that.
Special powers?
特別な力？
Oh, I do not doubt your word.
いや
そなたの言葉を疑っているのではない
I just thought that you were a Kunneietai.
てっきり そなたも我らと同じ
クンネイェタイだと思ったのでな
Kunn... What do you mean?
クンネ？
何だそれは
That is to say one who is under
the same divine protection
我らシャクコポル族と同じ
of the Great God Onvitaikayan as we
of the Shakukopolu Clan are.
オンヴィタイカヤンの
加護を受けし者のことだ
You do know the name of our god, do you not?
まさか我らが大神の名
知らぬわけではあるまい？
それは
Isn't that Witsalnemitea?
ウィツァルネミテアという
名ではなかったか？
That is the name of the loathsome
God of Misfortune!
それは忌むべきヌグィソムカミの名
余の前で二度とその名を吐くでない
Never speak that name before me again!
Witsalnemitea is a god of misfortune?
ウィツァルネミテアが
ヌグィソムカミ？
You really do not know?
本当に知らないのか？
This is quite different from the stories I have
heard, so I am in somewhat of a quandary.
聞いた話と大分違うので
戸惑っている
おかしなことを言う
That is a strange thing to say...
Listen carefully.
よいか？
Our Father, Onvitaikayan, is the
true god who created us.
大いなる父 オンヴィタイカヤンは
我らを想像せし真の大神
Witsalnemitea rebelled against our
creator and stole his position,
そして
ウィツァルネミテアとは
その創造主に造反し 食らい
and so there are those who
call him the "savior".
その座を奪いし者
ゆえに 解放者などと呼ぶ者もいるが
You truly did not know, did you?
本当に知らぬのだな
In the first place, did your priest
not give a distorted sermon?
第一 社を建てる時に ヨモルが歪曲した
ありがたい説法をしなかったのか？
Yes, at that time...
あの時は
ありがたい話を延々と語ってくれたから
She gave such a long, edifying sermon...
I felt so blessed that I nodded away.
ありがた過ぎて船を漕いでいた
フッ プッハハ アッハハハハハ
Do you mean that you fell asleep in
the middle of a ceremony?
そなた式典の最中に眠りこけていたのか
Is it really so amusing?
そんなに笑えることか？
うむ
Yeah, it's funny.
面白いぞ
Ah, I see!
そうかそうか
アッハハハ 聞くほどに不思議な男だ
You are as unusual a man as I had heard.
いや 私は
No, I am not...
Your Majesty, it is just about time...
聖上
そろそろ お時間にござりまする
Oh, already? And I was just
starting to enjoy myself.
もうそんな時間か
これから楽しくなるというのに
Hakuoro, I must now return.
ハクオロ
余はもう 戻らねばならぬ
そうか
I see, I am sorry to hear that.
残念だ
I am sorry too.
余も残念だ
We shall continue this next time.
この続きはまた次にな
Next time!?
Yes, it is a promise.
次？
うむ
約束だ
I will send Genjimaru for you again.
次もこのゲンジマルを迎えにやろう
Goodnight.
では
うむう
Witsalnemitea is a god of misfortune?
ウィツァルネミテアが ヌグィソムカミ？
Say, Hakuoro-san?
あの
ハクオロさん
Hakuoro-san?
Oh, I am sorry. I was deep in thought.
すまない
考え事をしていた
What's wrong?
どうした？
Are you sure you should be
spending so much time here?
いつまでも
ここにいて大丈夫なんですか？
Ah, it is all right.
I can always count on Benawi.
ベナウィは頼りになるからな
You used to be less skilled with that before.
You have improved quite a bit.
以前はもっとぎこちない感じがしたのに
随分と腕を上げた
Huh?
私なんてまだまだなのに
Oh, I still have much more to learn.
そんなことはない
That's not true. You have helped
everyone out quite a bit.
エルルゥのおかげで
皆随分と助けられている
そ そんなこと ないですよお
Oh, it's not like that!
あ　兄者
Huh? Brother!
What's wrong?
どうした？
Ah, nothing.
いや 何でもない
Eruruu, did you prepare what I asked you for?
エルルゥ 頼んでたやつは出来て
あ はい すぐに
Yes, I'll go get it right now.
You don't look well.
顔色が悪いな
この２人に酌をされると
When those two serve me drinks,
I just can't seem to say no.
どうもはめを
しゅん
Here you go, my lord!
若様どうぞ
-さっすが若様
-んぐ んぐ ぶはあ
Nice going, my lord!
My lord!
若様
I guess we were horsing around quite a bit.
よほど馬鹿騒ぎしたらしい
When morning came, we were all in a pile.
朝になったら 皆ぶっ倒れていた
ふうん
あつっ
Eruruu, isn't it ready yet?
エルルゥ まだか
Yes, here you are.
はい
お待たせしました
Is this it?
これか
Yes!
はい
Drink it down in one gulp.
ぐっと飲んでください
What the heck is this!?
何だこれは
Medicine for a hangover, right?
２日酔いの薬だろ
Couldn't you make it taste better?
もう少し 飲みやすくならないのか
Oh, was it bitter?
ええと
苦かったですか？
そうだ
Oh, I know! Some honey...
蜂蜜を
Here you go. Blub, blub, blub...
それでは
とろとろとろとろとろーっと
Aruruu drinks her medicine when I do this.
アルルゥも
こうすると飲んでくれるんですよ
ものすごい臭いがするぞ
It smells really awful.
Don't worry. It will go down smoothly, I'm sure.
大丈夫
口当たりはいいはずですから
きっと
Maybe...
多分
-しかし
-ううう
But this is...
これは
Oh well...
さてっと
待て兄者 どこへ行く
Wait, Brother! Where are you going?
いやあ
Well, it is about time I was going.
そろそろ行かないとな
オボロ
Oboro, drink it all down now.
ちゃんと飲んでやるんだな
You... You're not going to
see me through this?
み 見届けないのか
I am not.
見届けない
Well, I guess you don't have
to drink it after all.
あの
やっぱり飲まなくていいです
It seems I am not nearly a full-fledged healer.
私 やっぱり一人前には
程遠いみたいですから
It's all right, I realize now...
いいんです
分かってましたから
Oboro, drink it!
オボロ 飲め
Are you telling me to die!?
俺に死ねと言うのか
People do not die so easily.
人はそう簡単には死なん
ぬうっ
My lord! My lord!
若様 若様あ
オボロ
Oboro, from now on, do not give in
so easily to provocation.
これからは簡単な挑発に乗るな
-にっひっひ なあっ お おおお
-んあ
Oh! How unusual!
Patrolling by yourself, are you?
あら
珍しい　お一人で見回りですの？
No, that is not what I am doing.
いや そういうわけではないが
In that case, won't you join me?
でしたら
私に付き合っていただけません？
So you're drinking too?
お前も酒か
No, I am afraid it is too early for that.
いやあ さすがに昼間からは
You are very humble for the ruler
of a large realm, aren't you?
今や大国のオウルォが
謙虚なことですわねえ
あっ おい
H.. Hey!
-もっと堂々と振る舞うべきではありませんこと？
-お前 もう酔って
Shouldn't you behave more assertively?
You're already drunk.
Oh, I wouldn't consider this drunk.
この程度では
飲んだ内には入りませんわあ
Sire!
-聖上
-えっ
どうした？
What's wrong?
あら
You were not in your chamber.
部屋におられなかったので
外出する際は某に警護をと
I am to protect you whenever you go out.
Touka, this is the castle town!
トウカ ここは城下だ
You are unprotected, Sire.
聖上はあまりに無防備
There is no telling when you
might be ambushed.
どこに伏兵が潜んでいるやも
分かりませぬ
ウ ウフ ウフフ
伏兵ねえ
Ambushed...
How did you get into this castle, knave!?
貴様どうやって城に入った
It is all right, no need to worry about him!
いや こいつはいいんだ
Are you perhaps a new concubine?
-その 新しい側室の方でしょうか
-某はお側付きだ
I am his BODYGUARD!
あ それはそれは はい
Ah, me, is that so? Yes!
それで 今日はどうした？
So what brings you here today?
I am supremely grateful for your continued
patronage, Emperor Hakuoro.
ハクオロ王には
毎度ご贔屓感謝の極みにございます
I have managed to obtain a
very rare item, you see,
本日は
大変珍しい品が手に入りましたので
and I thought you should by all means
have a look at it, yes.
ぜひオウルォにお目通しをと
参上したした次第です はい
キュウ キュウ
It's so cute!
可愛い
んんっ くすぐったい
That tickles!
ウフ
-わ ああ わあっ
-キュウ
ンフ
This is a mikyuum?
これはミキューム
I am surprised that you know of it.
Yes, it is.
よくご存じで はい
How did you ever manage to
capture this sacred beast?
あの霊獣を一体 どうやって？
それは
Well...
Actually, this is my first time dealing
with such a creature too,
いえ 私も初めてですから
詳しいことは分かりません
so I'm afraid I do not know the full details.
So they really do exist!
-キュウキュウ キュウ キュウキュウ
-本当にいたんだ
ふうん
Is it really such a rare animal?
そんなに珍しいものなのか？
I hear they live in ravines where
man cannot enter.
なんでも 人が足を踏み入れることも
出来ない渓谷に住んでるとか
It has been said that they bring good fortune
and protect against calamities.
幸運を呼び 災いから守ってくれるという
言い伝えもあります
You are very well informed, yes.
よ よくご存じで はい
It is quite a rare animal.
っとまあ大変珍しいものでございます
What do you say?
いかがでございましょう？
Ah, well, we already have one big eater, so...
いやあ既に一匹
大食らいもいることだしな
I am sorry, but...
せっかくで悪いが
Oh, please, Mister!
-そんなあ おじさま
-えうう はう はう うう
No, it is not a necessity.
いや やはり必要の無いものだ
But, Your Majesty!
しかし聖上
必要とか必要無いとか
可愛いとか可愛くないとか
It's not a matter of it being necessary or
unnecessary, or cute or not so cute...
What are you talking about?
何を言っているんだ
Well...
まあ
Actually, I seem to recall Grandma saying that
its liver can be used to cure any illness.
-そういえばおばあちゃんが
-うん？
その肝はどんな病気にでも効く
薬になるって言ってたような
Yes, yes, I should have mentioned that earlier,
but that is just so! It cures all illness...
はいはい 申し上げるのが遅れましたが
まさにそれ　万病に
I'll buy it!
買った
Oboro-san?
オボロさん？
Is that story true? Then it should
cure Yuzuha's illness too!
その話本当か
だったらユズハの病にも
えっと
Well...
The story of its medicinal properties
seems to be true, but...
薬だというのは本当みたいです
でも
I don't care, as long as it makes
her even a little bit better.
少しでも良くなるのなら構わん
If that animal's liver can do it...
こいつの肝があれば
-むうっ
-キュウウ
Oh, you mustn't do that!
Do not look at it with blood in your eyes.
ああいけませんです
そんな血走った目で見たら
わあっ
My ears!
耳が
あ あれは 普段は大人しいのですが
That thing, it's normally very quiet,
-危険を感じると
-ああっ
but when it senses danger...
-あああ ああああ ああ
-あっ 待って
Oh, wait!
Hold it!
待て
あああ 売り物が
My merchandise!
グルウウウウウウウ
フン
Aru-chan...
アルちゃん
It smells sweet.
甘い香り
あむ
It's delicious!
おいしい
はぐっ うん
Oh, my... Who could this be?
まあ
誰かしら
キュウ キュウ
Oh...
グル
グルウウウ
ウフッ
You were hungry, weren't you?
お腹が空いていたのね
-キュキュウキュウ
-おお
Oh!
アハッ
くすぐったい
It tickles...
Brother?
お兄様
ええい
So this is where you escaped to...
こんな所に逃げてきたのか
Brother?
お兄様？
さあ そいつを渡してくれないか
Here now, won't you give it over to me?
キュウ キュウ キュウキュウキュウ
キュウキュッ キュウ
C'mon, Aruruu, won't you give it to me?
アルルゥ
そいつをこっちのよこしてくれないか
No!
なっ そうだ
たくさんの蜂の巣と交換しよう
I know, I'll trade you for a
bunch of honeycombs!
You don't have any honeycombs.
オボロ蜂の巣持ってない
なあっ
-キュウウ キュウ
-あ
Gachatara says he'd be killed.
ガチャタラ殺されるって言ってる
ガチャ タラ
Gachatara?
Yes...
この子の名前
That is his name.
How cute!
可愛い
Its liver is a valuable medicinal.
そいつの肝は 貴重な薬になるんだ
Please understand what this means.
この意味を分かってくれ
I don't understand.
分からないです
ユズハ？
Yuzuha?
Yuzuha-sama...
ユズハ様
I don't want to be cured if we must do that.
ユズハは
そんなことをしてまで
治りたくはないです
What are you saying!?
なっ 何を言ってるんだ
I sense a very nasty feeling coming from you.
お兄様から とても嫌な感じがするの
I don't like you when you're like this, Brother.
そんなお兄様
嫌い
-あああ
-ああ 若様
My lord!
Oboro...
オボロ
Brother! Tell them, Brother!
兄者
兄者からも言ってくれ
You are outnumbered.
お前の負けだ
Lemme play!
私もお
ガチャタラ
Gachatara...
ウフッ 私も混ぜて
Let me play with him too!
ウフフッ
Have they already given it a name?
もしかして
名前を付けてしまったんですか？
What if they have!?
それがどうした
A mikyuum considers the one that gives
it a name its master, yes.
ミキュームは名前を付けた人を
主人と認識してしまうのです はい
May I speak to you a moment?
少しよろしいでしょうか
だいたい…
えっ 何だその額は
What!?
That's an outrageous price!
そうおっしゃられましても
Nevertheless...
Brother!
兄者
What can I do?
仕方ないな
Thank you for your continued patronage, yes!
毎度ありがとうございますです　はい
-こっち　はあー
-ウハハ ウフフッ うわあ　アハッ ウフフフ
ウフッ
Brother, I'm so glad!
兄者 俺は嬉しいんだ
I think it was great of you to say that!
兄者がああ言ってくれて
本当に良かったと思ってる
Okay, I understand, go to bed.
ああ分かったから もう休め
I swear to stay by your side forever!
-俺は 兄者と共にあることを永遠に誓う
-んん んああ
I've heard that over and over.
それは何度も聞いた
Please make Yuzuha happy.
そして ユズハを幸せにしてやってくれ
He seems to be quite drunk.
酔いが深いようだ
Dori, Gura, take good care of him.
ドリィ グラァ
ちゃんと面倒見てやるんだ
Yes, Sire!
-はい
-はあ
It's all clear.
もういいぞ
I should have known you'd
sense my presence.
さすがはハクオロ王
Well, shall we go?
さ 行こうか
Thank you for coming, I have been waiting.
よく来たな
待っていたぞ
Genjimaru, you may leave us for a time.
ゲンジマル
しばらく席を外しているがよい
No, it is my duty to protect you, Your Majesty.
いえ
聖上の身をお守りするのが
某の務めなれば
I have not come here as sovereign.
Do not worry, you may leave us.
余はオウルォとして
ここに来ているのではない
いいから外すがよい
But, Your Majesty!
しかし聖上
くどいぞ
Enough! Will you not obey my order?
余の命が聞けぬか
Yes, Your Majesty.
御意に
Good grief! He is such a worrier.
まったく
どうも心配性でいかん
What is wrong?
どうした？
Are all the Evankulga like that?
エヴェンクルガというのは
皆あんな風なのか？
So I have heard. Is it a problem?
そう聞いているが？
それがどうかしたか
No...
いや
Good grief... You see what it is like
being followed everywhere.
まったく
年中付きまとわれる身にもなるがよい
I know what you mean.
そうだな
Anyway, I would like to spend
some time chatting with you.
それに 今宵は２人だけで
ゆるりと語りたい気分なのだ
Tell me...
そなた
How many wives do you have?
室は何人いる？
How many, you ask...
何人いるかと言われても
It should not be a question of how many!
そんなの何人もいるわけがないだろう
Hm? Why not?
なぜだ？
Whether or not you have an heir will
affect the fate of your country.
跡継ぎがいなければ
国の存亡に関わるのだぞ
The fact is I am still single.
なぜも何も
私はまだ独り身だ
You are?
そうなのか？
I heard that you were a lustful
king who had many wives.
既に幾人もの室を迎えている
好色王という話だったが
Where did you hear a story like that?
どこからそんな話を
You need not keep it a secret.
隠さずともよい
There is no shame in a man loving a woman.
女子を愛しく思うのであれば
恥ずべきことではないぞ
The stories you have heard are wrong.
その話は間違っている
What? Do you not like women?
なんだ
女子は好かんのか
He is seeming all the more lewd...
いよいよもって好色王だな
待て
Wait! You have the wrong idea!
何を勘違いしているんだ
Ah, another thing!
あっ そうだ
What now?
今度は何だ
Why are you wearing such a mask?
そなたはなぜ
そのような仮面をしておるのだ？
Well, I've tried several times to remove it,
but it will not come off.
何度か外そうとしたんだがな
駄目だった
Let's see.
-ほお どれ
-ああっ
Don't pull it!
引っ張るな！
ふむ　本当に外れないのだな
It really won't come off, will it?
I wanted to see your face without the mask.
そなたの素顔を
見てみたいと思ったのだがな
What a shame...
残念だ
Well, what about you?
You have your face hidden too.
それを言うならクーヤも
素顔を隠しているだろうに
Me?
余も？
ああ そういえばそうであった
Ah, yes, you are right.
I seldom remove it when I am with
people, so I simply forgot.
めったに人前で外さなから
つい忘れておった
Forgive me.
許すがよい
Is this all right?
これで よいであろう？
A woman?
女
Do I look like a man to you? Do you...
余のどこが男だ
-そなた
-いや
No, I did not mean it that way.
そういうわけではないが
What a rude man! Did I say even
once that I was a man?
失礼な男だ
余は一度でも自分を男だと言ったか？
No, you did not, but...
それはそうだが
ふむ
Well, I do know what it is
you are trying to say.
しかし
そなたの言わんとしていることは分かる
A young girl like me lacks dignity.
このような小娘では
威厳も何も無いであろうからな
It is a sorry state of affairs.
情けない話であるな
If I were not so immature,
I would not need to wear this.
余が未熟者でさえなければ
このような物を被らずともよいものを
ああ 夜風が肌に当たって気持ちいいな
The night wind feels wonderful against my skin.
大いなる父
オンヴィタイカヤンの加護を失い
After losing the protection of the
Great God Onvitaikayan,
the people of this world began
fighting each other.
この世に人同士の争いが生まれた
While the strong seek to gain supremacy,
the powerless are continually victimized.
強き者が覇権を求める一方
力を持たぬ者は常にその犠牲となる
And we, the powerless Shakukopolu Clan,
そして 力を持たぬ
我らシャクコポル族は
have for many years been trampled
upon and oppressed
オンヴィタイカヤンの
寵愛を受けていた嫉妬から
due to jealousy inspired from the favor
we received from Onvitaikayan.
長きに渡り蹂躙され虐げられ続けてきた
No one comes to our rescue.
誰も助けてはくれなんだ
The gods have abandoned us.
神々は我らを見捨てたのだ
But it turns out that we were not
completely abandoned.
だが
全てに見捨てられていたのではなかったのだ
We have gained power that is irreplaceable.
我らは
何物にも代え難き力を得たのだからな
Why are you telling me this?
なぜ私に そんな話を
Oh, this won't do.
ああ いかんな
I seem to have become caught up in my story.
つい話すことに
夢中になってしまったようだ
When I am with you, I feel like
telling you everything.
お前と一緒にいると
何でも話してしまいたくなる
You are a strange man indeed.
不思議な男よな
Kuuya Amrulineulka, Sovereign of Kunekamun...
クンネカムン王
アムルリネウルカ・クーヤ
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
魂から結びつき　私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
The Rebel Army